# Shlomi Domnenko

## Software Engineer

shlomidom@gmail.com (+972)54-2557736 Portfolio in shlomi-domnenko ShlomiRex



Software and cyber security engineer with 3 years of experience. Successfully implemented and scaled software projects for 500 million users. I love solving challenging problems and I know I can handle pressure. I'm looking for great people to work with and brilliant ideas to implement as a software developer. One of my greatest accomplishments is "learn how to learn" through dedication and research.

### Experience

Meta, Production Engineer

07/2022 - 10/2022 | Tel Aviv

Facebook Lite Group, Service Infrastructure Team

- Led the migration from Apache Mina to Netty framework in Java Spring Boot, achieving a 30% reduction in network latency. Optimized the Facebook Lite backend architecture by writing critical infrastructure code, using Netty multiplexing pipelines to improve API gateway performance and scale systems for over 500 million users across 14 regions.
- · Worked on monolithic project using Mercurial SVC, learned to search for internal solutions and ask questions in open-source projects, optimize and test code, fix large merge conflicts and use Tupperware (in-house alternative to Kubernetes) for progressive rollout of changes.

#### Bank Hapoalim, Backend Engineer

01/2022 - 07/2022 | Tel-Aviv

Backend Java Developer, responsible for developing the business website

- Optimized and implemented new RESTful APIs with Java Spring Boot, safely removed legacy APIs, and resolved unplanned issues on time, earning positive customer feedback. Used Splunk for log analysis and troubleshooting, proactively addressing issues outside sprint planning.
- Coordinated clear communication between front-end, mainframe, QA, and product teams. Streamlined issue management, cutting backlog by 50%, and quickly mastered systems to deliver timely solutions.

#### Check Point, Security Analyst

04/2020 - 01/2022 | Tel-Aviv

Threat Response Core Group, Research & Development

- Raised protection score from 82% to 94% for customers for selected CVEs, resulting in the passing of the critical 'Security Effectiveness Test' by researching threats and creating new protections for customers, beating competitors, resulting in customer signing contract and I got a bonus.
- Responsible for researching and creating protections against CVEs in the Check Point SIEM IPS/IDS by malware research and network traffic analysis, and using tools such as Metasploit, Wireshark, OWASP, Burp, Snort, YARA rules. Closely worked in Linux, Windows environments.
- Automated the creation and deployment of anti-bot protections with Python, Gitlab CI/CD, deployment of Jenkins jobs and docker containers, and VM setup in VMWare vSphere. Used SQL and analyzed Kibana customer's data with elastic search to determine false positives.
- Gained significant knowledge in various networking protocols. Communicated with other companies for support with API (VirusTotal)

#### Education

Master of Science (MSc), Computer Science & Mathematics, The Open University of Israel

**Currently Studying** 

GPA: 90. Research project: research & develop video synthesis machine learning model with high temporal cohesion.

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Computer Science & Mathematics, Ariel University Graduated. GPA: 82. Cyber Security Program

Graduated

Currently studying for CompTIA Network+, CCNA certifications as well as AWS Cloud Practitioner.

## **Projects**

seefood-app, A Silicon Valley parody app that takes picture with phone and tells you if your food is a hotdog or not hotdog.

The app was built using Android SDK & Java and communicates with the server, the server runs Flask and ResNet-50 classifier (written in Python).

sorting-algo-visualizer, Visualize sorting algorithms, it also plays sounds while the algorithm is running

Written in pure JavaScript. Includes quick sort, radix sort, heap sort, and more. You can try it yourself, click on the link.

shlomios, A basic x86 operation system written from scratch that runs C kernel

Written bootloader in assembly and the kernel in C. Runs on QEMU and BOSCHS emulators. Can write to VGA display.

ocr-font-classifier-model, Machine learning model that predicts the types of fonts of text in images

Written in Python with TensorFlow. Training used 1164 images, validation 520 images with validation accuracy of 96%.

MessageU, Secure messaging and file transfer app with end-to-end encryption

Written the client in C++ and the server in Python, allowing secure encrypted communications by using RSA key exchange, AES CBS for encryption/decryption and SQLIte3 for storage of keys and encrypted content.